Golden Age Sci-Fi mss., 1935-1956 LMC 2742
Lilly Library
Golden Age Sci-Fi mss.
1935-1956
Lilly Library
LMC 2742
1 Box
Collection consists of revised and copy-edited typescripts, galley proofs, and correspondence for approximately fifty original short stories and novellas from the "Golden Age of Science Fiction" published in Galaxy, Beyond Fantasy Fiction, Other Worlds, Fantasy & Science Fiction, Unknown Worlds, Universe Science Fiction, IF, and other magazines.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into the following series: I. Writings; II. Transcripts--Radio; III. Correspondence.
Scope and Content Note
Writings contain drafts and proofs of stories and novellas by authors including: Poul Anderson, Stephen Arr, E. B. Battles, Eando Binder, James Blish, Robert Bloch, Anthony Boucher, Robin Brown (Robert Zacks), Algis Budrys, Cleve Cartmill, Alan Cogan, Groff Conklin, William Crawford, George Damler, Charles V. De Vet, Miriam Allen DeFord, Charles Dye, Daniel P. Galouye, Randall Garrett, D. V. Gilder, Harry Harrison, Roy Hutchins, David Keller, Willy Ley, Edward W. Ludwig, Sam Merwin, Jr., William Morrison, Charles Munoz (as T. P. Caravan), Stanley I. Rowson, Rick Sargent, Robert Sheckley, Walt Sheldon, Evelyn E. Smith, Ralph Spencer, Ian Watson, Edward Wellen, Richard Wilson, and Donald Wollheim (as David Grinnell). Transcripts are from radio broadcasts of science fiction tales from Poul Anderson and Charles Dye. Correspondence includes exchanges of letters between Harry Harrison and Naomi Mitchison, as well as between Harry Harrison and Claire M. Smith. The Miscellaneous series contains galley proofs of a lengthy bibliography of science fiction authors.
Acquisition Information
Acquired: 2010
Science fiction; Fantasy; Fantasy literature, English; Pulp literature; Pulp literature, American; Anderson, Poul, 1926-2001.; Bloch, Robert.; Boucher, Anthony, 1911-1968.; Budrys, Algis, 1931-2008; Crawford, William L., 1911-1984; Harrison, Harry, 1925-; Mitchison, Naomi, 1897-1999; Muñoz, Charles, 1926-; Sheckley, Robert, 1928-2005; Smith, Evelyn E.
- Writings (Box 1)
  Arrangement
  Divided into two subseries: Stories; and Novellas. Stories arranged alphabetically by title of publication, then title of story. Novellas arranged alphabetically by title of each novella.
  - Stories (Box 1)
    - Beyond (Box 1)
      - "Age Cannot Wither," by Cleve Cartmill, Jan. 1955 (Box 1)
      - "Dragon Lady," by Evelyn E. Smith, Jan. 1955 (Box 1)
      - "It's Colder Inside," by E. B. Battles, Jan. 1955 (Box 1)
      - "The Paynim's Flute," by Ralph Spencer, Jan. 1955 (Box 1)
      - "Sizzlestick," by Sam Merwin, Jr., Jan. 1955 (Box 1)
      - "Stream of Consciousness," by Roy Hutchins, Jan. 1955 (Box 1)
      - "They," by D. V. Gilder, Jan. 1955 (Box 1)
    - Fantasy and Science Fiction (F&SF) (Box 1)
      - "I've Got A Little List," by Randall Garrett, Nov. 1955 (Box 1)
      - "The Lysenko Maze," by David Grinnell, July 1954 (Box 1)
      - "Playground," by William Morrison, July 1955 (Box 1)
      - "Sriberdegibit," by Anthony Boucher, undated (Box 1)
    - Galaxy Monthly (Box 1)
      - "The Amateurs," by Alan Cogan, July 1955 (Box 1)
      - "Big Stupe," by Charles V. De Vet, March 1955 (Box 1)
      - "Country Estate," by Daniel F. Galouye, August 1955 (Box 1)
      - "Deadhead," by Robert Sheckley, July 1955 (Box 1)
      - "Don't Shoot," by Robin Brown, April 1955 (Box 1)
      - "For Your Information," by Willy Ley, Aug. 1955 (Box 1)
      - "Galaxy's Five Star Shelf," by Groff Conklin, July 1955 (Box 1)
      - "Inside Story," by Richard Wilson, June 1955 (Box 1)
      - "Man's Best Friend," by Evelyn E. Smith, April 1955 (Box 1)
      - "Mr. President," by Stephen Arr, Nov. 1953 (Box 1)
      - "One Way," by Miriam Allen DeFord, March 1955 (Box 1)
      - "Origins of Galactic Advice," by Edward Wellen, April 1955 (Box 1)
      - "Princess and the Physicist," by Evelyn E. Smith, April 1955 (Box 1)
      - "Spoken For," by William Morrison, July 1955 (Box 1)
    - IF (Box 1)
      - "Watershed," by James Blish, May 1955 (Box 1)
      - "Your Time is Up," by Walt Sheldon, June 1955 (Box 1)
    - Other Worlds (Box 1)
      - "The Dog Who Wanted To Go Home," by Rick Sargent, September, 1955 (Box 1)
      - "Man In the Moons," by Eando Binder, September, 1955 (Box 1)
      - "Politician," by Stanley I. Rowson, September, 1955 (Box 1)
      - "Proof-Load," by George Damler, September, 1955 (Box 1)
    - Unknown Publications (Box 1)
      - "Everything You Were Afraid to Know About/ Pournelle," by Robert Bloch, undated (Box 1)
      - "Fantastic Adventures with Amazing," by Robert Bloch, undated (Box 1)
      - "Ghost Lecturer," by Ian Watson, undated (Box 1)
      - "A Kiss For Uranus," by Elron Stuttered, undated (Box 1)
      - "The Laughing War," by David H. Keller, M.D., undated (Box 1)
      - "The Special Effectiveness of George Pal," by Robert Bloch, undated (Box 1)
      - "Songs of Gurre," by J. P. Jacobsen, translated from the Danish by Poul Anderson, undated (Box 1)
      - "The Turkish Barber," unidentified author, undated (Box 1)
      - "Why Artists Go But Grey," unidentified author, undated (Box 1)
  - Novellas (Box 1)
    - Michaelmas by Algis Budrys, (pp. 1-150), undated (Box 1)
    - Michaelmas by Algis Budrys, (pp. 151-246), undated (Box 1)
    - Purple Chaos by Frederick Van Cortlandt and William Crawford, ca., 1935 (Box 1)
    - The 7 Shapes of Solomon Bean by Edward W. Ludwig, 1983 (Box 1)
    - The Shoemaker of Lan by TP Caravan, 1955 (Box 1)
    - Skyfall by Harry Harrison, (pp.1-145), undated (Box 1)
    - Skyfall by Harry Harrison, (pp.146-288), undated (Box 1)
    - Skyfall by Harry Harrison, (pp.289-431), undated (Box 1)
    - Spawn by Robert Bloch, (pp. 1-116), undated (Box 1)
    - Spawn by Robert Bloch, (pp. 117-222), undated (Box 1)
    - Spawn by Robert Bloch, (pp. 223-357), undated (Box 1)
    - Wheelworld by Harry Harrison, (pp. 1-99), undated (Box 1)
    - Wheelworld by Harry Harrison, (pp. 1-177), undated (Box 1)
- Transcripts-Radio (Box 1)
  - "Inside Earth," by Poul Anderson (misspelled "Paul"), 1953 (Box 1)
  - "Syndrome Johnny," by Charles Dye, 1953 (Box 1)
- Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Harrison, Harry to Mitchison, Naomi, 1968-1974 (Box 1)
  - Mitchison, Naomi to Harrison, Harry, including a few responses from Harry Harrison and Violet Williams, 1968-1974 (Box 1)
  - Smith, Claire M. to Harrison, Harry, 1969 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous (Box 2 (Oversize))
  - Bibliography, science fiction authors, galley proofs (Box 2 (Oversize))